PROGRAMMER RESUME



Block C, Plot No-56, Vell- Gijhore Sectore -53, Noida, UP, 263139, India. Contanct: 8958510532, rjdev1988@gmail.com

IT Professional with 6+ years of experience in developing web, batch, and business intelligence solutions for diverse industry clients. Highly instrumental in all phases of the SDLC, with expertise in web development and data structures. Successful in developing It solutions, optimizing business procedures, processes, and productivity.

Rajdev Prasad,

[Software Engineer, Contact: 8958510532, 8126898831, rjdev1988@gmail.com]

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, September 2021 – Present in Chetu India Pvt., Block- A- 206, Sector-63, Noida, UP.

- Developing ASP.NET web application using Telerik reports, xml, SQL, procedure and working with DAL business logic, use Trello board to manage task. .net framework 4.5.2
- Developed .net core 6 Weather web application and intergraded, consume third party API in web application.
- Developed Application on Azure DevOps and working Scrum board and Kanban board to following
 the approach of Azure DevOps Services. Azure Boards, Git repos and collaborate to build code with
 pull requests and file management.
- Azure DevOps Services use to a set of modern dev services to plan, track, build, test, and deploy applications with agile tools, CI/CD, and security.
- Developed Stripe Payment with tax service, API in Application, Graphs Implementation in application, using ASP .Net Core 5, 6, 7, C#, JavaScript, HTML, jQuery, SQLServer2018.
- Developed R Language Application using shiny app with graph, data analytics for business and API Centric projects.
- Developed .Net Core-6. o, Including payment integration API Stripe Payment transactions for sale subscription plan web applications.
- Develop and maintain 2+ customized data-centric web applications and services using ASP.NET CORE -5.0, API Centric projects, C#.NET, MVC, MS SQL, Oracle.
- Created and applied UI requirements utilizing ASP.NET, JS, J Query, .NET Framework, HTML, and CSS.
- Monthly Training Test successfully passed certified in latest technologies Agular, JS Node, MS SQL from Chetu India Pvt in 2021-2022.

Programmer, September 2016 - August 2021 in SS IT Solutions, Sector-57, Noida, UP

- Develop and maintain 8+ customized data-centric web applications and services using ASP.NET, C#.NET, MVC, MS SQL.
- Create and apply UI requirements utilizing ASP.NET, JSP, JSF, Spring Framework, Hypernet HTML, and CSS, JSP.
- Collaborate with business analysts, users, and federal agencies to collect requirements and provide implementation.
- Implement Business Intelligence/SQL solutions to integrate disparate data sources towards a centralized datastore.
- Improve the performance of all SQL and online components to ensure strict service level agreements, timely response and data reliability.

Programmer, June 2013 - August 2016 in NexGen, Sector 63, Noida, UP

• Built database objects (T-SQL, triggers, stored procedures, functions, and jobs) to support responsive data access.

- Developed and optimized programs performance using ASP.NET, C#.NET, and MS SQL, which streamlined processes.
- Implemented office management applications that worked in good profits.
- Programmed customized software solutions that helped customers to use their capital and manage risk more effectively.

ASDE, April 2012 - May 2013 in Rate Gain IT Solution, Sector-57, Noida, UP

- Built database objects (MS Excel, Access, SQL, triggers, stored procedures, functions, and jobs) to support responsive data access.
- Ensured fulfilment of business data-extraction requirements developing custom reports and search optimization in different data from internet.
- Provides raw form of the data for development requirements.

EDUCATION

NIIT South Ex., New Delhi, India

GNIIT (Software Engineering), May 2014

Kumaun University, Nainital, UK., India

M.A(Economics), August 2013 B.A(Economics, Political Science, Sociology) July 2011

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Azure DevOps Services: Scrum working Channal and Kanban Board.
- **Programming:** C#, .Net MVC, ASP.Net (Core and Advance web Application), XML, Core Java, JSP, J2EE, J2ME, JSF, Spring Framework, Hibernate Framework, MySQL.
- **DBMS:** SQL Server, MS Access, and MS SQL, Oracle.
- **OS:** Windows Server 2016, Windows 10.